

42, V.le 4 Novembre, Senigallia, Marche, 60019, Italy

□ (+39) 3393101652 | **□** proch92@gmail.com | **□** proch92 | **□** micheleproverbio

Summary

Currently working as a Data Scientist in Rome, Italy. 5+ years work experience in IT and Data Science specializing in Machine Learning and Computer Security. Passionate about Linux, open source and inclusive free software development. Knowledge enthusiast constantly learning physics, math and natural sciences with an attentive look at the future.

Work Experience ___

Integris SpA - Cons. Bridgestone EMIA

Rome, Italy

DATA SCIENTIST May. 2020 - Current

- · Designed and developed a ML model for tyre mounted sensors in Pytorch using high performance data cleaning pipelines in Julia.
- Built OLAP dashboards in Microsoft Insights for cloud analytic.
- Developed data pipelines on the Azure data lake using Apache Spark and Databricks notebooks.
- Created a dashboard for online analytic using Microsoft PowerBI.
- Designed and developed a ML model for tyre wear using time series modeling in Pytorch.

Onit Group Cesena, Italy

System Administrator - Data Scientist

Apr. 2015 - Dec. 2018

- Managed and re-engineered the IT infrastructure for Confargricoltura Forlì-Cesena-Rimini from hardware to software to IT service.
- Designed an Al algorithm for a Master Data Management software in order to match records from different databases on a semantic level, using Natural Language Processing techniques with Gensim.
- Hot-swapped a kernel image on a critical Linux/CentOS server remotely.
- Managed internal and external Active Directory infrastructures (including Microsoft Exchange, IIS, SQL Server and others.)
- · Main team referral for Linux systems.

Teachings_

MongoDB and NoSQL for BigData, 24 hour course on MongoDB part of a specialization degree program on 2019 Data Science.

Milan, Italy

Ubuntu Linux and Trashware, From hardware to software. All around course to jump start the town 2012 Trashware program.

Senigallia, Italy

Education

Università di Bologna

Cesena Italy

MASTER'S DEGREE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Oct. 2015 - Mar. 2020

- Key courses choices focusing on Artificial Intelligence and Data Science.
- Thesis in Continual Learning. Study and implementation of the Growing Dual Memory technique.

Università di Bologna

Cesena Italy

Oct. 2011 - Mar. 2015

· Thesis in authentication systems security

BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Certifications

Apr. 2020 Machine Learning, Stanford Machine Learning course held by Professor Andrew Ng

Stanford, Coursera

Extracurricular Activity _____

CeSeNA (CeSeNA Security Network and Applications)

Cesena, Italy 2011 - 2020

MEMBER

- Took part in numerous international CTF and Wargame competitions on hacking and computer security.
- Studied and practiced Assembly reverse engineering for executable exploiting.
- Studied and practiced numerous web and network security exploits like SQL injection and Cross Site Scripting among others.
- Took part in lectures for the students of the University of Bologna, teaching Ethical Hacking and Techniques.



Languages

WRITING, LISTENING AND SPEAKING

- Italian: Native
- English: Proficient

Programming Languages

GENERAL PURPOSE PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

- Python: Excellent
- C: Proficient
- C++: Proficient
- Julia: Experienced
- · Bash: Experienced
- Js, Java, Lua: Familiar

Data Science

LIST OF TECHNOLOGIES I HAVE EXPERIENCE WITH

- general purpose: Pandas, Numpy, Scikit, Apache Spark, Kafka
- ML: PyTorch, Tensorflow, Gensim, Flux.jl
- DB: MongoDB, Hive, MySQL, Google Firestore
- Dashboarding: PowerBI, Databricks, Tableau

Sysops

LIST OF TECHNOLOGIES I HAVE EXPERIENCE WITH

- · Cloud: GDP, AWS
- Sys Admin: Active Directory, Apache, Nginx, Firewalls
- Systems: Arch, Ubuntu, CentOS, Debian, MSW Server, MS Windows

Web Development

LIST OF TECHNOLOGIES I HAVE EXPERIENCE WITH

- Frameworks: Angular 7, Bootstrap, Middleman
- Markup: CSS3, HTML5
- Template Engine: Jinja2, Django

Competitions.

2018	VarGroup Hackaton , Al-powered knowledge base and on-site operator assistance. Sponsored by Apple, Cisco Webex.	Riccione, Italy
2017	VarGroup Hackaton, Machine Learning in breaks industry R&D. Sponsored by IBM Watson.	Riccione, Italy
201*	IT Security, Wargames with CeSeNA security group. RuCTF, DEFCON Qualifiers, Insomnihack and 0ctf	Cesena, Italy
	among others.	
2009	RoboCup Jr., National high school robotics competition.	Turin, Italy